Sarah M. Pearson

408 Fieldcrest Dr. Nashville, TN 37211 (615) 424-9907 SarahP@me.com

Meticulous and creative Executive Assistant with over eleven years experience in the entertainment industry. Additionally responsible for event planning, office strategy & organization, and recording of sales & historical charting data. Implements new ideas into a company's dynamic in order to optimize budgets and create work efficiency. Works with CEO's, executives and business affairs department to explicate writer contracts and Billboard Singles figures. Trained on several customized software programs. Proficient on Mac/PC, Microsoft Office, Photoshop, and Final Cut Express.

Core competencies include:

- Database Management
- Adaptable in changing situations
- Ability to work in a team environment or individually
- Troubleshooting/Problem Resolution
- Implementation of new concepts
- Remarkable work ethic

- ■Outstanding office strategy management
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Rapidly acquires and applies new information
- ■Extremely organized
- ■Exemplary time management skills

EXPERIENCE

A&R Assistant Warner/Chappell Music Publishing January 2014– July 2014

Warner/Chappell Music, the global music publishing company of Warner Music Group, is home to a wide array of legendary songwriters and a rich catalog of contemporary hits and influential standards. With offices in more than 40 countries, Warner/Chappell provides deep expertise across a range of creative services and the most innovative opportunities for songwriters and copyright holders. With a history dating back more than 200 years, Warner/Chappell currently publishes and administers music from Beyoncé, Bruno Mars, Eric Clapton, fun., Led Zeppelin, Lionsgate Films, Madonna, Miramax Films, among many others.

Job Duties:

- Designed ads for industry magazines, and eBlasts (Photoshop/Illustrator)
- Coordinated catering, sound, and set up for A&R meetings
- Enter new song information including writer percentages and publishing line into File Maker Pro database
- Gather all co-writer label copy from music publishers and co-writers
- Manage calendar for Executive Vice President (calendar & time management)
- Greet and escort all guests for Executive Vice President

P/T Administrative Manager Patrick Joseph Music Publishing June 2013 – December 2013

Patrick Joseph Music is a Nashville based publishing company partnered with SONGS Music Publishing. SONGS has offices in LA, New York and London. In a 10 year period, Patrick Joseph produced 31 ASCAP and BMI award winning songs including the 1995 CMA Song of the Year "Strawberry Wine" and the 1997 ASCAP Pop Song of the Year "I Can Love You Like That."

Job Duties:

- In charge of paying all incoming bills from demo sessions and vendors
- Responsible for creating and sending invoices to co-publishers and vendors for payment
- Maintain bookkeeping records using QuickBooks
- Gather all co-writer label copy from music publishers
- Deposit checks into bank account
- Enter new song information including writer percentages and publishing line into File Maker Pro database

Executive Assistant EMI Music Publishing September 2001 – July 2012

EMI Music Publishing is the largest music publisher in the world, located in 30 countries, with more than one million musical compositions. They have a distinguished history in acquiring and managing the rights to compositions and songs creating one of the finest catalogs of musicians and music with works from the Beatles to Beyonce. EMI Music Publishing was acquired by Sony/ATV on June 29, 2012.

Job Duties:

- Coordinated, organized and managed all aspects for special events including parties for over 300 people, writer #1 parties, A&R receptions and holiday functions
- Researched, assembled and organized all EMI charted Billboard Singles from 1998-2007 into a database and promotional binder for distribution generating revenue
- In charge of writing and updating artist/writer biographies and discographies for EMI Wikipedia pages (HTML)
- Produced invitations and show flyers for EMI Events (Photoshop)
- Managed monthly activity of released albums/singles for archiving and reports (Word/Excel/Access/AS400)
- Project Manager for office renovations; liaison between EMI, General Contractor and Interior Design Firm
- Tracked, systematized and maintained the archiving of EMI Music Publishing Nashville history; singles and awards
- Enforced monthly travel & entertainment expense reports for Executive VP/GM and A&R staff
- Assembled, calculated and distributed Billboard Country Singles chart analysis to Nashville and NY staff
- Gathered all new writer Schedule A materials and deal points for distribution to legal and business affairs
- Responsible for coordinating all travel for Executive Vice President/GM
- Created, updated and organized weekly hold/cut/action file and database
- Photographed office headshots and EMI events

Catalog Coordinator Almo-Irving Music Publishing May 1999 – September 2001

Almo-Irving was the largest independent music publisher with offices in London, Sydney, Amsterdam, Paris and Hamberg. Founded by Herb Alpert and Jerry Moss in 1966 it grew from 200 copyrights to over 50,000 titles covering all musical styles before Universal Music Publishing purchased the catalog in 2001.

Job Duties:

- Assisted in preparing songs for local cataloging and federal copyright
- Created CD's for pitching to artists
- Assisted in answering a high volume of calls
- Responsible for duplication and distribution of new songs to song pluggers
- Organized and maintained tape and CD archives
- Responsible for timely delivery of pitch CDs to labels and producers

Mercury Records Nashville August 1999 – December 1999 Media Relations Intern

Mercury Records is an imprint of Universal Music Group Nashville. Founded in 1945 in Chicago it has been one of the most successful country labels since its start in Nashville in 1958. It continues to have a strong presence with new and old acts including Toby Keith, Shania Twain, Sugarland, and Billy Currington.

Job Duties:

Computer

- Updated itineraries and Nashville news weekly
- Sent out Mark Wills & Mavericks tour press materials
- Oversaw mailing of press materials to media publications
- Responsible for making and distributing itineraries and music reports for entire staff

SKILLS

compater.					
☑ Microsoft Word	⊠Excel	PowerPoint	Outlook	Adobe Acrobat	☑ Photoshop
✓ Social Networking	☑ PC/Mac	\square HTML	☑ CSS	☑ Final Cut Express	☑ Illustrator

EDUCATION

Belmont University

Nashville, TN Bachelor of Business Administration Major: Music Business Emphasis: Management

1997 - 2001